Have you ever over thought something so much that you ended up doing absolutely nothing?
Oh yeah.
My brain loves that strategy.
Step 1. Panic
Step 2. Panic about the panic.
Exactly. It's like our brain thinks thinking more will somehow magically fix everything.
My brain is like a broken search engine.
I ask one question and it opens 47 tabs of anxiety.
And none of them are helpful.
Not a single one.
Just emotional pop-up ads.
Today we're talking about how to stop overthinking, face fears, and take action in life.
Yeah, because I'm an expert at doing nothing due to overthinking.
Well, we'll get into that.
But first, let's introduce the topic.
So overthinking.
It's like the ultimate productivity killer.
Right?
It's like our brain is trying to protect us, but it ends up paralyzing us.
Last, yeah, my brain is like a helicopter parent.
Chuckles, okay?
So, let's dive into a personal story.
Oh boy, this should be good.
So, I used to be terrified of public speaking.
I would overthink every possible scenario.
Interrupting.
Oh, I can relate.
I once had to give a presentation and I was so nervous I forgot my own name.
Laughs.
That's amazing.
But for me, it was more like, what if I say something stupid?
Joakingly.
Oh, that's never happened to me.
Laughs, right.
But seriously, I had to face my fear and just start speaking.
And how did that go?
It was actually really liberating.
I realized that people aren't as judgmental as I thought.
Teasingly, yeah, until you say something stupid.
Laughs, hey, that's not the point.
Smirking, okay, okay.
So what's a common situation where people overthink?
Well, like when you're trying to make a big decision, like what career to choose.
Oh yeah, or what to eat for breakfast?
Laughs exactly.
Our brain can turn anything into a monumental decision.
Joakingly, I mean, what if I choose the wrong cereal?
Chuckles, right.
But seriously, it's like our brain is trying to weigh every possible outcome.
And that's when the anxiety kicks in.
Exactly.
So let's talk about why humans overthink.
Curiously, yeah, is it just me or is it a human thing?
Thoughtfully, I think it's a mix of both.
Our brain is wired to anticipate potential dangers.
Joakingly, like what if a dinosaur attacks?
Laughs, well, maybe not dinosaurs, but more like what if I fail?
Smirking, yeah, or what if I succeed and have to deal with the consequences?
Laughs exactly.
But seriously, our brain is trying to protect us, but it can get carried away.
Curiously, so how do we stop it?
Well, one strategy is to set a timer and limit your thinking time.
Joakingly, oh, like a thinking timeout.
Laughs exactly.
And another strategy is to focus on the present moment.
Thoughtfully, yeah, like mindfulness.
Exactly.
And finally, just take action.
Don't wait for perfection.
Excitedly, yeah, just do it.
Like Nike.
Smiling exactly.
And that's what we want to leave you with today.
Inspiringly, yeah, don't let overthinking hold you back.
Just take the leap.
Smiling, thanks for tuning in everyone.
Joakingly, and if you're still overthinking, just remember, it's not the end of the world.
Laughs, unless you're actually facing a dinosaur.
Laughs, then you're on your own.